# **FARNOOD FOROUDI**

## PRODUCT DESIGNER

farnood.me foroudi@gmail.com (+372) 5367 1295

## **Skills**

## Design

Illustration and UI graphics
Strategy and vision presentations
User flows

Concept sketches

Wireframes and mock ups

Motion design

Design systems principles

Style guides and pattern libraries

Design Ops

Localisation and RTL Support

## **Prototype**

Rapid prototyping Interactive flows Interactions and transitions HTML/CSS/JS prototyping

#### Research

Interviewing
Usability testing
A/B Testing
Statistical analysis

#### Tools

Sketch

Figma

Adobe Creative Suite

Principle App

Flinto

Origami

Zeplin Abstract

Zeroheiaht

Zeroheigh

InVision Mixpanel

Taplytics

Tableau

Google Analytics / Firebase

MindNode

Aha!

Jira and Confluence

Ping Pong

## **Education**

BS Software Engineering Shomal University, Amol, Iran 2005-2011

## **About**

I'm a product designer from Iran, now living in Tallinn, Estonia. I have 8 years experience designing and crafting digital products. I've been working in multiple popular Iranian and international products, defining their product strategy, design approach and solutions for the users. I have a solid background in interface design, user experience and interactiomn design.

## **Work Experience**

### Monese / Product Designer - Onboarding Experience

AUG 2019 - PRESENT, TALLINN, ESTONIA

Designing the whole Monese onboarding experience, including sign up, KYC and, account opening, to be easier, faster, and shorter. With a data-driven approach utilizing quantitative data, A/B testing and also user tests I managed to improve the important key metrics like drop-offs, completion rates, and more. I also contribute to the core design system and, accessibility guidelines.

## Alibaba Travels / Head of Mobile Applications (Product and Design)

FEB 2019 - AUG 2019, TEHRAN, IRAN

Built a product development process to manage the complete redesign of the former app, alongside with the expanding of the product coverage and development of new mobile-only features, with speed and future scalability in mind • I was leading the product designers in my team to deliver a whole new app experience based on user research and usability test • I worked with the marketing team to utilize the marketing automation tool inside the apps • I helped the company to recruit, shape and build the product design team to form a decentralized chapter of product designers • I started the Alibaba's Design Language System project across the whole company.

### Kian Capital Management / Product Design Lead

FEB 2018 - FEB 2019, TEHRAN, IRAN

Was responsible for taking the digital banking from ideation to production. This included vision setting, conducting research, designing solutions, creating high-fidelity visuals, prototyping new ideas, presenting work to our cross-functional teams, and overseeing implementation • I designed the KYC and Onboarding process to tackle the problems of bank account opening procedures in Iran • I successfully designed a robust design structure for Kian's future product expansion • I initiated and led the first version of Kian Design Language System • I recruited and led the entire team of product designers.

#### **Dunro** / Product Design Lead

SEP 2015 - FEB 2018, TEHRAN, IRAN

I developed the product's vision to evolve Dunro from a simple local business search engine to a complete location-based city guide platform • I created, recruited and lead the product design team • I contributed to core values like Targeted Advertisement Platform, Rate and Review System, Dunro's Gamification Platform, Add New Locations flow, Social Feed and the Superusers Program • The DAU and user retention rates successfully increased by more than 40% in 6 months after introducing our social and gamification features • Our app users boosted from 100K to 500K in 1 year • During my time, Dunro won the Iran Web and Mobile Awards, twice.

### Seeb Mobile Technologies / Co-Founder, Product Designer

OCT 2013 - MAY 2015, TEHRAN, IRAN

I co-founded Seeb as a mobile solutions agency to offer mobile application development, consultancy, and product design to Iranian companies • We successfully designed and developed mobile apps by contract for great companies in Iran like NetBarg (Coupon Deals), Parsian Bank (Mobile Bank App), Buyex (Online Apparel Shop), Fidilio (Popular Restaurant Review App) • We also launched a series of in-house applications like SeebStore (A payment solution for Iranian users with no access to visa/master), Tehran Air (Air Quality Check app), Golabi (An iOS trivia game) • I was working as a multidisciplinary individual working mainly on product design and coordinating the projects.

## Mapna Group / UI-UX Designer

OCT 2012 - SEP 2014, TEHRAN, IRAN

Working on internal enterprise portals over the Microsoft SharePoint foundation. During my time at Mapna, I successfully turned the majority of traditional paperwork workflows into fully automated workflows in collaboration with the Systems and Quality department engineers. I was also in charge of designing and developing the company's website which I successfully designed, developed, and launched it over the .NET platform.